Guide to the James Lippincott Goodwin Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- James L. Goodwin "Old" Correspondence, 1912-1953; Series V
  - Pine Acres Farm, Martin Martino, 1929-1938 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    Checks drawn to the order of Martin Martino, Pine Acres Farm.
  - Pine Acres Farm, Petty Cash, 1935-1936 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    Statement for petty cash for years, 1935-1936.
  - Plantations, 1915-1946 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    H. H. Chapman, Professor of Forest Management, Yale University, advising on the management of plantations; Placement of orders with the Keene Forestry Associates for White Spruce and White Pine Transplants; Correspondence between James L. Goodwin, W. O. Filley, Forester, Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, and J. E. Riley, Jr., Associate Pathologist, United States Department of Agriculture with respect to the Work Progress Administration; Men Surveying for Blister Rust Infection on J. L. Goodwin's property; Bay State Nurseries, North Abington, Massachusetts; Purchase of Pine trees from Goodwin; Orders for transplants from the Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station; Fall River Herald News, advertisement for Christmas Trees; Statement relating to Trees Blown Down in Hurricane from Pine Acres Farm, September 21, 1938; 1938 Income Tax Allowance for Hurricane Losses; Correspondence with Professor Ralph C. Hawley, Yale Forest School, about accounting for Forestry work done on plantations; Statements concerning Pine Acres Farm Spruce Plantation 4E; Compartment Conversion Tables.
  - Plantations-Income Tax, 1938-1940 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    Appraising hurricanes loss in plantation; Wind Damage Cost Summary, 1938; Pine Plantations regarding Pine Acres Farm; Correspondence with R. C. Hawley relating to damage reports and figure appraisals for income tax purposes.
  - R, 1928-1932 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    Map of Humboldt State Redwood Park; Confidential report from the Bureau of Census regarding Pine Acres Farm; Statements of Cost of Horses for Pine Acres Farm, Supplies and Produce Cost; Comparative Statement of Maintenance Accounts, January 1 - June 30, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1934-1938; R. C. Hawley advising on forestry accounting practice; Statement regarding Information of Cordwood, Lumber, and Christmas Tree Operations; Statement of Maintenance Accounts, Pine Acres Farm, 1942, 1942-1943-1944; 1944-1945.
  - Rocky Neck Property (Box 19, Folder 37)
    W. O. Filley, Forester, Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, advising Goodwin that the subscribers to the State Park Project in East Lyme, would meet to organise; An agreement between J. L. Goodwin and others with respect to purchasing 650 acres of property located in the town of East Lyme for a State Park development; Rocky Neck Trust, Receipts and Expenditures, May 20, 1930; Memorandum regarding the Rocky Neck Trust and correspondence concerning contributions and taxes for the property; Acknowledgement of checks to Goodwin from W. O. Filley, Trustee of Property, and snapshots of the beach; W. O. Filley informing J. L. Goodwin that the House and Senate passed the bill for an appropriation for the purchase of Rocky Neck as a State Park.
  - S, 1917, 1930-1941 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    Order from J. L. Goodwin for the Sundstrand Adding Machine, Contract between the Standard Oil Company of New York and J. L. Goodwin; Loan on property requested by William A. Spicer, Attorney; Clement Scott, Hartford-Connecticut Trust Company, corresponding with J. L. Goodwin in regard to purchasing land for the purpose of a Tennis Club; Contributions to Storms Community Church.
  - Scotty Puppies, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    Correspondence mainly with Mrs. Gertrude Putman relating to the care of J. L. Goodwin's puppies, also correspondence with the C. W. Lines Company for food for the puppies.
  - Shaker Pines, Hazardville, Connecticut, 1936-1938 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    Booklet entitled "Shaker Pines at Point Lake, Hazardville, Connecticut"; J. L. Goodwin corresponding with Goodwin B. Beach about Amos D. Bridges and Son Company's timber track, Shaker Pines; Growth Figures-according to areas of Forestry Department-Survey; Results of Timber Cruise of Shaker Pines by W. F. Schreeder, Forest Engineer; Statement of Area, Volume Per Acre and Total Volume; History of Shaker Pines Forest, Enfield, Connecticut; Timber Cruise - State Forestry Department; Report on Shaker Pines, Hazardville; Map of Shaker Pines showing Softwood, Old Field, Hardwood, and Mixed Hardwood; Snapshots of Shaker Pines; Timber Estimates; Memorandum of Timber Salvage in Connecticut.
  - Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation - Preliminary Company and Organization, 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    Memorandum "Plan for Conserving the Shaker Pines in Enfield"; Correspondence between Edgar L. Heermance and J. L. Goodwin relating to the purchase of Shaker Pines from Amos Bridges and Son, Hazardville, Connecticut; Notice to Subscribers of Shaker Pines Project from Edgar L. Heermance, Secretary, Connecticut Forest Park Association filing a Certificate of Incorporation by Goodwin B. Beach, James L. Goodwin and Edgar L. Heermance, July 14, 1937; Statements of Receipts and Disbursements, August 2, 1937; List of Subscriptions for shares of stock.
  - Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation, 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    Subscription of stock paid to and after July 29, 1937; Statement regarding special account, Connecticut Forest and Park Association; List of Subscribers; Release of Mortgage from Amos D. Bridge's & Sons from Bancroft and Martin Rolling; Receivers Deed; Hadleigh H. Howd, Receiver, Estate of Amos D. Bridge's Sons, Incorporated to Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation.
  - Shaker Pines, 1937-1941 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    Snapshots of Shaker Pines, 1937; Minutes of Directors Meetings, 1937-1940; Description of the Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation Property; Acknowledgment from Edward Bradley, Trustee Permanent Trust Fund, Connecticut Forest and Park Association to Shaker Pines Forest Corporation for check covering principal amount of Demand Note; J. L. Goodwin corresponding with George A. Cromi, C. C. C. Camps, Somers, Connecticut, in regard to demonstration plots at Shaker Pines Forest; J. L. Goodwin informing Edgar L. Heermance of marking pines for future cuttings at Shake Pines; Notice to Shaker Pines Stockholders of the Annual Meeting; Discussions pertaining to salvaging Timber after hurricane 1938, and negotiations for sale of wind blown timber; Agreement between Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation and Charles H. Soule about his purchasing the wind-blown timber; Termination of Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation; Statements of Estimated Liquidating Balance Sheet; Cash Received and Expended Earnings-Statement from time of Incorporation to Time of Dissolution; List of Assets and Liabilities, (Creditors and Debtors) Certificate from the State of Connecticut relating to the Preliminary Dissolution.
  - Shaker Pines Tax Returns, 1937-1940 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    Various Tax Returns, 1937-1940, Estimated Liquidating Balance Sheet, June 8, 1940; Final Certificate of Dissolution; Minutes of Directors Meeting and of Special Meeting, June 8, 1940; Directors voting for termination of Corporate Existence.
  - Shaker Pines, Tax Returns, 1937-1941 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    Cancelled Checks and Statements, 1937-1940; Ledger Accounts, 1937-1940; 1939 Return of Capital Stock Tax; Certificate of Classification, 1937; Amendment to an agreement between Shaker Pines Forestry Corporation and Charles H. Soule.
  - Society of Connecticut Craftsmen, 1938, 1940, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    Program Booklet of exhibition and sale of contemporary Crafts, by member of the Society of Connecticut Craftsmen and Guest Exhibitions from the New York Society of Craftsmen; List of Articles sold; Statement relating to Norfolk Sale; List of contributing members and members of the Society.
  - Society of Connecticut Craftsmen, 1940-1942, 1945, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    Contributing members of the Society; Active member list; Sales and exhibits, November 18, 1940; Membership tickets; Magazine, Connecticut Progress; Elmer T. Thienes, President, Society of Connecticut Craftsmen, Incorporated, corresponding with J. L. Goodwin with respect to paying the Society's Note of indebtedness; List of Directors.
  - State Park Possibilities, 1912 (Box 19, Folder 47a)
    Correspondence with officials of many towns of Connecticut accumulating information for state part sites.
  - Stocking, Edson, 1926-1935, 1940-1942, 1947-1950 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    Correspondence with Edson Stocking, Superintendent, Pine Acres Farm, relating to various business matters of Pine Acres Farm; Personal matters regarding health and vacations; matters concerning employees withholding exemption certificates, forestry work and time sheets.
  - T, 1940-1943 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    Price list of Terell's Aquatic Nurseries, and orders from E. C. Stocking.
  - Taxes, Hampton, 1920-1921, 1929-1940 (Box 20, Folder 50)
    J. L. Goodwin purchasing land from Thomas Riley; Tax Forms for property, 1922-1923, 1928-1940; Correspondence with John Scott and Roger W. Davis about tax list; Checks and Tax Receipts.
  - Timber, North Eastern Salvage Ticket, 1938-1940 (Box 20, Folder 51)
    1938 Lease between J. L. Goodwin and Federal Surplus for Commodities Corporation for land located in the Chaplin tract, to North Eastern Timber Salvage Administration for logs storage, sawmill site, and lumber yard; Various tickets from the North Eastern Timber Salvage Administration, Boston, 1939; Invoices from New England Forest Emergency Project, delivered to J. L. Goodwin; Invoices of scale sheets, rental of storage sites; Public Vouchers for purchases and services to J. L. Goodwin from the Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation, North Eastern Timber Salvage Administration; W. Robert Dinneen, Unit Supervisor, North Eastern Timber Salvage Administration, notifying J. L. Goodwin of the expiration of his timber purchase amendment contract; Lease held by the Federal Surplus Commodities Corporation from W. Robert Dinneen.
  - Tyron, 1926 (Box 20, Folder 52)
    Map of Gillette Woods, Tyron, North Carolina, prepared for Gillette Estates, Incorporated; History, "Romance of Gillette Estates", by Lawrence Gillette; Deed of Gillette Estates Incorporated, State of North Carolina, Polk County; W. M. Ellsworth, Gillette Estates, Incorporated offering an option to buy several lots in Gillette Woods, Tyron, North Carolina.
  - U, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 53)
    General correspondence relating to the United States Department of Agriculture with booklets Agricultural Chemistry and Soils and Fertilizers, and Price List of Publications; Henry A. Donavan, Clerk, United States Department of Agriculture, corresponding with J. L. Goodwin about his request for copies of the Soil Survey Reports of Lake County, Florida, and Moore County, North Carolina; Dividends paid by the United States Steel Corporation.
  - Wild Life - Hampton, 1939, 1941, 1943, 1945, 1946, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 54)
    alph E. Eddy, Assistant, Superintendent, American Fish Culture Company, acknowledging J. L. Goodwin's order for Brook Trout; Partial list of Domestic Buyers of Fresh Water Turtle Traps; Permit for Killing deer from Connecticut State Board of Fisheries and Game, 1941, 1943, and 1945; Copy of "Conservation News Service", by Connecticut Wild Life Federation, John P. Leonard, Editor.
  - Wildes, Walter, 1931-1939 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    Personal correspondence between J. L. Goodwin and Walter K. Wildes, Classmate of J. L. Goodwin relating to business, renewing old acquaintances, vacations, family matters and Walter Wildes applying for membership in the University Club.
  - Yale Forestry School, 1910 (Box 20, Folder 55a)
    "Southern Trip of the Senior Class" written by James L. Goodwin in his senior year of the Yale Forestry School, to Clarks Caldwell Parish, Louisiana with publications from the Yale Forestry School News, October 6, 1966, also photographs of class members.
  - Yale University, 1924-1925, 1925-1935, 1937, 1948, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 56)
    Edwin Oviatt, President and Treasurer, Yale University Publishing Association, Incorporated corresponding with James L. Goodwin regarding the election of Goodwin as a Governor of the Yale Publishing Association; Acknowledgement to J. L. Goodwin for contributing to the "Yale Alumni Weekly", 1935; Four Year Plan for the "Yale Alumni Weekly"; Plans for Class Reunion for Class of 1905.
  - Yale University, 1952-1953 (Box 20, Folder 57)
    Frank Squire, Classmate at Yale, 1905, corresponding about various classmates; Sponsorship of Juris Padges by the Class of 1905.
  - Y. M. C. A., 1929-1930, 1931, 1933, 1936-1939, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 58)
    A. S. Knowles, Senior Boy's Work Secretary, Y. M. C. A. corresponding with J. L. Goodwin about sizes and material needed for the construction of rustic seats for Camp Rainbow Chapel; Electric light situation; Improvements; Controversies over Negro Boys and White Boys being admitted to the camp during the White Boy's Stay; Report, "Colored Boys at Camp Rainbow"; Possible withdrawal of Camp Jewell, Incorporated from the Corporate Rights in New Hampshire; Flowage Rights; Proposed Water Supply Tank; Purchasing additional property for Camp Rainbow from Mr. Simon Waicunas; Snapshots of boat given to Camp Jewell; Camp Rainbow and Camp Jewell Rehabilitation; Minutes of Meetings; Staff reports for 1947; Camp Property Agenda, February 3, 1947; Report to the Executive Director, June-August, 1947.
  - Y. M. C. A., 1941-1950 (Box 20, Folder 59)
    Receipts and acknowledgment to James L. Goodwin for money contributed; Charles F. T. Seaverns, Chairman, Camp's Property Committee asking for contributions to the Camp Rainbow Improvement Fund; Membership cards of J. L. Goodwin; Elections of J. L. Goodwin as Trustee for Camps Property Committee; Brochure of 1944 Camp Projects; Minutes of Meetings of the Camp's Property Committee; New Camp Site; Report to the members of Camp's Property Committee; H. F. Fisher, Play Time, Incorporated, Purchasing Camp Rainbow.
  - X, Y, Z, 1917-1940 (Box 20, Folder 60)
    William H. Taft of New Haven, corresponding with J. L. Goodwin in regard to organization of the National War Work Council; Y. W. C. A., 1926-1927, correspondence between J. L. Goodwin and Elinore Sharpless, and Primrose Wolverton, Y. W. C. A., with respect to landscaping, lo-Cation of building for camp, plantings and surveying property for camp site; One letter to the Zoological Society of Philadelphia from J. L. Goodwin with respect to magazines and other literature.
- James L. Goodwin "New" Correspondence, 1928-1967; Series VI
  - B, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Correspondence between J. L. Goodwin and Newton C. Brainard in regard to cutting and sawing logs, with price list for cost of job; Burlington, King and Duke, Incorporated, Management of Farms and Country Estates, doing accounting on Pine Acres Farm.
  - B, 1947-1948 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    K. E. Barraclough requesting a copy of the bulletin, by Collin G. Spencer, "The Practical Forest Farm"; Harold Sweeton, Superintendent, Great Pond Nursery, corresponding with Basile Realty Company relating to Timber Estimates of Basile Saw Mill.
  - Bill Boards, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with George H. Fallon and Clifford Davis of the House of Representatives about Board Control.
  - D, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    One letter of Eugene Dietzgen from J. L. Goodwin in regard to surveying compass.
  - F, 1923-1949 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    General correspondence relating to forestry matters; American paper and Pulp Association Report on the facts of cost of commercial reforestation; Worlds Forestry Congress, organized by the International Institute of Agriculture and the Italian Government; E. N. Manna, United States Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, corresponding with J. L. Goodwin about the measurement of tree volume by planimeter.
  - G, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    J. A. Gibbs, United States Department of Agriculture, Soil Conservation Service, corresponding with J. L. Goodwin about visiting J. L. Goodwin's woods in Carthage, North Carolina.
  - H, 1925-1952 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    E. C. Haff, Forester, Aerial Surveys, Timber Management, Forest Products, corresponding with J. L. Goodwin about aerial photography; Charles Dowing Lay, President, Housatonic Valley Planning Association notifying members of the third Annual Meeting of the Association.
  - I, 1940, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    J. S. Illick, Syracuse University, Professor of Forest Management, seeking information of the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association, to be used as a study of Forestry Association; Tabulations of Forestry in Ireland, 1957.
  - J, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    I. Sidney Jenkins, Louisville, Kentucky, inquiring about a forester to take charge of his tract of land, 12,000 acres, near Louisville, Kentucky
  - K, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    Dr. Clarence F. Korstian, Duke University, Forestry School, and J. L. Goodwin relating to J. L. Goodwin securing a publication entitled "Forestry in Private Lands in the United States", distributed with compliments of the National Lumber Manufacturers Association.
  - L, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    L. S. Luquer, Jr., Student at Trinity College, seeking summer employment in forestry.
  - M-Mc, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    Massachusetts Forestry Association continuation despite the depression; James L. McConaughy, Governor of the Connecticut, about the State park and Forest Commission attempting to secure the resignation of Doctor Kienholz, State Forester; J. L. Goodwin congratulating Harry A. McKusick on his new position as State Forester of Connecticut; J. L. Goodwin contribution to Moore County Hospital, North Carolina.
  - N, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    General and business correspondence relating to National Christmas Tree Growers Association, Incorporated; Notice of meetings of the National Resources Council of Connecticut; Proposed revision of By-Laws of Natural Resources Council of Connecticut, Incorporated; James G. K. McClure, Secretary, Education and Development Fund, Farmers Federation, North Carolina, relating to financial aid for the Cherokee Indians of North Carolina; R. J. Preston, Director, Division of Forestry, North Carolina State College of Agriculture and Engineering; correspondence with J. L. Goodwin about the Senior Class visiting his forest in North Carolina; Annual Report of the Northeastern Logger Magazine and contributions for the magazine; "Draft Deferment for Lumber Industry Employees" bulletin, Northeastern Lumber Manufacturers.
  - National Parks Association, 1948-1966 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    Correspondence between William P. Wharton, National Parks Association, Executive Committee and J. L. Goodwin relating to J. L. Goodwin becoming a member of the Association and acknowledgment of contributions to the organization of Mr. Goodwin.
  - O, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    Oregon Company Timber Survey, April, 1932; List of prices and valuation of timber of the Oregon Company, Hartford, Connecticut.
  - P, 1924-1948 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    R. B. Parmenter, Extension Forester, Massachusetts State College of Agriculture, requesting the bulletin "The Practical Forest Farm" relating to work done on Mr. Goodwin's farm at Carthage; Memorandum regarding payments for pastures and forestry, 1937; Copy of Pine Statistics for Pine Type, 1900-1923, showing value of Pine Plantations.
  - Professional Engineers and Land Surveyors, State of Connecticut, 1951-1965 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    Roster of Registered Professional Engineers and Land Surveyors, January 31, 1951; Certificates of Registration Cards; J. L. Goodwin, 1936-1964; Notice of a meeting to discuss establishment of a State Professional Organization for Land Surveyors.
  - R, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    Correspondence between Lawrence W. Rathbun, Society for the Protection of New Hampshire Forests and J. L. Goodwin with respect to visiting Mr. Goodwin's forest land in Carthage, as well as in Hartford; L. C. Rawson, American Forest Products Industries, inviting James L. Goodwin to attend the Annual Meeting and luncheon.
  - S, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    Correspondence relating to Save-The-Redwoods-League with respect to financial contributions and receipts of payment; News Articles, "New Redwood Champ-Tallest in the World"; and "Save the Redwoods League"; Correspondence between Dean George A. Garratt, Yale School of Forestry, and J. L. Goodwin with respect to Platt Hill State Park; Statement to members of the State Park and Forest Commission from H. H. Chapman.
  - Surveying Jobs, 1932-1948 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    Correspondence between J. L. Goodwin and Stanley K. Dimock, Allen Manufacturing Company, Hartford, about Mr. Goodwin surveying his property; Correspondence between J. L. Goodwin and various other people pertaining to surveying work.
  - T, 1937-1967 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    Connecticut Tree Protective Association Draft of the Certified Tree Expert Bill introduced in the Connecticut Legislature in accordance with action taken at the Association's Annual Meeting, January 6, 1937; Notice to members of Connecticut Tree Protection Examining Board of renewal of licenses and fees; Notice regarding expiration of arborist license; Roster of Licensed Tree Works, Connecticut Tree protection Examining Board, January 1, 1958.
  - W, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    J. Atwood Whitman, Consulting Forester, Glendon, North Carolina, performing survey work and timber estimates for Mr. Frederick U. Conrad, Hartford, Connecticut on his property in Tennessee.
  - Y, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    H. H. Chapman, Professor of Forest Management, Yale University, writing J. L. Goodwin that the Nominating Committee of the Connecticut Forestry Association desires to nominate Mr. Goodwin as a Director.
  - Yale University, 1925-1966 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    Correspondence between Professor Henry S. Graves, Yale Forestry School and J. L. Goodwin regarding surveying work for Mr. Goodwin; J. L. Goodwin Activities.
  - Yale University - School of Forestry, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    An Article by J. W. Toumey, Professor of Siliviculture, Yale University, "Proposed Plan for the Future Development of the Demonstration and Research Forestry of Yale University"; Yale Alumni Weekly pertaining to Yale Demonstration and Research Forest; Acknowledgment letters to J. L. Goodwin for donations to the Endowment Fund Campaign; J. W. Toumey, shipping two year old white pine seedlings to J. L. Goodwin; J. L. Goodwin giving an account of his career in forestry to be considered by the council for his nomination to the Society of American Foresters; Summary of Cuttings of Wood Products from Pine Acres Farm, January 1945 to October 1950.
  - Y. M. C. A. - Camp Jewell, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    Y. M. C. A. of Hartford - North Colebrook Camp Project Proposed Budget; Agenda for Outdoor Center Committee.
- James L. Goodwin "Personal" Correspondence, 1882-1967; Series VII
  - Correspondence, 1882-1898 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Letters written by James L. Goodwin and received by him from his parents and brothers at the time he attended Groton School concerning his daily school activities, friendship with Franklin Delano Roosevelt and complilation of a daily weather map; Mr. Goodwin's Baptismal and Confirmation Papers; 1895 Cutler School Report.
  - Correspondence, January, 1895-1935 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Groton School letters to Mr. Goodwin's parents about the physical and educational programs; annual cards sent from 1921-1935 by Mr. Peabody to his former school boys; Mr. Goodwin's conditions at the Yale Forestry Camp in Louisiana in 1910.
  - Photographs, 1892-1905 (Box 22, Folder 3)